Paetin S. Nelson

Paetin.Nelson@gmail.com | 503.729.0144 | Portland, OR GitHub: https://github.com/paetinspier | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/paetin-nelson

Projects

Pacific Standard Website / Full Stack Website

July 2021 - August 2021

Designed and developed user-friendly residential builder website, including implementing new design layout and aesthetics to attract page views and improve user experience. (HTML, Bootstrap, PHP, and MySQL)

Bluetooth RC Car / Electronics Project

April 2019 - May 2019

Built Bluetooth RC car using a breadboard and Arduino Uno microcontroller. Coded the Arduino Software (IDE) to allow the car to be multidirectional as well as utilize the proximity sensors on the front of the car. Linked the Arduino to an IOS app for remote control. (C++)

Redlands Yelp App / Android App

April 2020 - May 2020

Worked with a team to create an app modeled after the Yelp app. Led the design and development of the directions button, which allowed users to locate desired restaurant using Google Maps. Completed using Android Studio for the mobile application. Initiated the use of Slack and GitKraken to manage communication and project deliverables. (Java)

Skills

- Fluent in Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git
- Proficient in React.js, MySQL, Bootstrap, PHP, Microsoft Suit, Python
- Communication

- Cross-functional teamwork
- Code Optimization
- Problem Solving
- Computer Science Knowledge

Education

University of Redlands / B.S. in Computer Science, Minor in Mathematics
Graduated April 2022, Redlands, CA

Cleveland HS / High School Diploma

Graduated June 2018, Portland, OR Focus: Mathematics and Physics 3.5 GPA & 4-year varsity athlete

Relevant University Courses

- Data Structures and OOP
- Web Application Development
- Algorithms
- Mobile Development
- Software Engineering
- Calculus 1, 2, 3
- Discrete Mathematics
- Differential Equations

Work Experience

University of Redlands

January 2020 - April 2022

- Grading Assistant and Student Tutor for the Director of Computer Science and Mathematics
 Meteor Building Company, Construction Laborer
 May 2017 Present
 - Perform general labor, carpentry, drywall, siding, painting, etc.

The Far Post, Sales Associate

May 2018-August 2018

Assisted shoppers, offered product knowledge, handled merchandising and sales transactions.
 Garden Monsters, Cook & Window Server
 May 2017-August 2017

• Interacted with customers in a positive, upbeat manner in a busy and fast paced environment.

Extracurricular

- 4-year NCAA Division III Men's Soccer
 - o 2021 SCIAC Men's Soccer Champion
 - NCAA D3 Men's Soccer Championship Sweet 16 finalist
- Oregon State Champions in 2017 and 2018, 4th in 2017 Far West Regionals tournament